<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Macos on Adler Medrado's corner of the web</title><link>https://adlermedrado.com.br/tags/macos/</link><description>Recent content in Macos on Adler Medrado's corner of the web</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adlermedrado.com.br/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ollama vs LM Studio vs llama.cpp — A No-BS Guide to Running LLMs Locally on macOS</title><link>https://adlermedrado.com.br/posts/llm_local_llamacpp_mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adlermedrado.com.br/posts/llm_local_llamacpp_mac/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s cut the fluff: if you care about privacy, speed, and having full control over your stack, running LLMs locally is no longer optional — it’s survival. Cloud’s nice until it’s not. Especially when your data is the product and your API bill explodes overnight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I put this guide together because I wanted &lt;strong>LLMs running locally&lt;/strong>, even with limited hardware — no vendor lock-in, no middlemen sniffing packets, just raw local compute. And yes, I run this stuff daily on a MacBook Air M1 with 16GB RAM. Modest? Yep. Enough? Hell yes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Erro incômodo com o Postgresql no Mac</title><link>https://adlermedrado.com.br/posts/erro-incomodo-com-o-postgresql-no-mac/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adlermedrado.com.br/posts/erro-incomodo-com-o-postgresql-no-mac/</guid><description>&lt;p>Esse é um post bem curto que resolvi escrever depois de me incomodar com um erro esquisito no Postgresql no Mac após a
atualização para o MacOS Sierra.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O servidor do Postgresql estava funcionando OK mas o client cli me retorna o erro abaixo sempre que eu o executava:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://adlermedrado.com.br/posts/images/1*nKXkh2PzTW85hhl59x3-3w.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WTF?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eu costumo usar o &lt;em>homebrew&lt;/em> para instalar a maioria das coisas no meu mac, primeiramente eu pensei que fosse algum
problema com algum link simbólico incorreto, então eu executei o comando abaixo para ver se resolvia:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>